Guide to the Native American Educational Services, American Indian Press Association Records 1970-1976
University of Chicago Library
Native American Educational Services. American Indian Press Association Records
1970-1976
1 linear foot (2 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection consists of press releases produced by the American Indian Press Association. The collection forms part of the archives of Native American Educational Services,
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The American Indian Press Association was a news-gathering organization devoted to increasing the participation of Native Americans in the creation and consumption of newspapers. Notable staff members included Rose Robinson, Charles Trimble, and Richard LaCourse. The AIPA was in operation from 1970 until 1976.
The AIPA records were held by the Native American Education Service (NAES) until 2008. Established in Chicago in 1974, NAES College aimed to improve the leadership of Native communities and to ensure that tribal knowledge, traditions and values play a major role in the higher education of Native students. Before closing its doors in 2007, NAES College offered a single degree, a Bachelor's of Arts in General Studies with an emphasis in Public Policy, and tribal knowledge, community service, community development and leadership.
Scope Note
This collection consists of press releases produced by the American Indian Press Association.
Related Resources
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
American Indian Press Association; NAES College; Indians of North America; Indians of North America -- Education (Higher); Indian universities and colleges -- United States
INVENTORY
- AIPA Press Releases, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AIPA Press Releases, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- AIPA Press Releases, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)